type Question = {
    question: string;
    answers: string[];
    correctAnswer: string;
  };



  export const introanatomydata = {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Human Anatomy is the study of structure of Human body and acts as foundation to study other basic and clinical sciences. Main approaches to study Anatomy are Clinical, Systemic and",
        answers: ["Radiology", "Imaging", "Regional", "Pharmacotherapy", "Physiotherapy"],
        correctAnswer: "Regional"
      },
      {
        question: "While studying Anatomy, it is divisible into Gross Anatomy, Histology and Embryology. Histology primarily focuses on:",
        answers: ["Microscopic structures", "Plant biology", "Medical practice", "Animal anatomy", "Biochemistry"],
        correctAnswer: "Microscopic structures"
      },
      {
        question: "Main divisions of Anatomy are Regional, Systemic and Clinical. What is the primary focus of regional anatomy?",
        answers: ["Organ systems", "Specific part", "Cellular structures", "Biochemical processes", "Genetic sequences"],
        correctAnswer: "Specific part"
      },
      {
        question: "Which branch of Anatomy deals with study of the macroscopic structure and function of the body as it relates to the practice of medicine and other health sciences.",
        answers: ["Clinical anatomy", "Surface anatomy", "Regional anatomy", "Systemic anatomy", "Imaging anatomy"],
        correctAnswer: "Clinical anatomy"
      },
      {
        question: "What lies under the skin and what structures are perceptible to touch (palpable) in the living body at rest and in action is studied in",
        answers: ["Clinical anatomy", "Surface anatomy", "Regional anatomy", "Systemic anatomy", "Imaging anatomy"],
        correctAnswer: "Surface anatomy"
      },
      {
        question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Head, gaze (eyes), and toes directed",
        answers: ["posteriorly (backward)", "laterally", "anteriorly (forward)", "medially", "obliquely"],
        correctAnswer: "anteriorly (forward)"
      },
      {
        question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Arms adjacent to the sides with the palms facing",
        answers: ["laterally", "medially", "laterally", "anteriorly", "posteriorly", "obliquely"],
        correctAnswer: "anteriorly"
      },
      {
        question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Lower limbs close together with the feet parallel and",
        answers: ["laterally", "posteriorly", "anteriorly.", "medially", "obliquely"],
        correctAnswer: "laterally"
      },
      {
        question: "In Anatomical descriptions, there are three imaginary vertical planes.Two are parellel and which one is at right angle to these parellels?",
        answers: ["median", "sagittal", "frontal/coronal", "transverse", "median sagittal"],
        correctAnswer: "frontal/coronal"
      },
      {
        question: "Which anatomical plane divides the body into right and left halves?",
        answers: ["Transverse plane", "Frontal plane", "Sagittal plane", "Median plane", "Coronal plane"],
        correctAnswer: "Median plane"
      },
    ] as Question[]
  };
  

// export const introanatomydata = { 
//     questions: [
//     {
//         question: "Human Anatomy is the study of structure of Human body and acts as foundation to study other basic and clinical sciences. Main approaches to study Anatomy are Clinical, Systemic and",
//          answers: ["Radiology", "Imaging",
//          "Regional",
//          "Pharmacotherapy",
//          "Physiotherapy"],
//         correctAnswer: "Regional"
//     },    
//     {
//         question: "While studying Anatomy, it is divisible into Gross Anatomy, Histology and Embryology. Histology primarily focuses on:",
//         answers: [ "Microscopic structures",
//          "Plant biology",
//          "Medical practice",
//          "Animal anatomy",
//          "Biochemistry",],
//         correctAnswer: "Microscopic structures"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "Main divisions of Anatomy are Regional, Systemic and Clinical. What is the primary focus of regional anatomy?",
//         answers: ["Organ systems", "Specific part",
//         "Cellular structures",
//         "Biochemical processes",
//         "Genetic sequences"],
//         correctAnswer: "Specific part"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "Which branch of Anatomy deals with study of the macroscopic structure and function of the body as it relates to the practice of medicine and other health sciences.",
//         answers: ["Clinical anatomy",
//         "Surface anatomy",
//         "Regional anatomy",
//         "Systemic anatomy",
//         "Imaging anatomy"],
//         correctAnswer: "Clinical anatomy"

//     },
//     {
//         question: "What lies under the skin and what structures are perceptible to touch (palpable) in the living body at rest and in action is studied in",
//          answers: ["Clinical anatomy",
//          "Surface anatomy",
//          "Regional anatomy",
//          "Systemic anatomy",
//          "Imaging anatomy"],
//         correctAnswer: "Surface anatomy"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Head, gaze (eyes), and toes directed",
//         answers: ["posteriorly (backward)",
//          "laterally",
//          "anteriorly (forward)", 
//          "medially", 
//          "obliquely"],
//         correctAnswer: "anteriorly (forward)"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Arms adjacent to the sides with the palms facing",
//                 answers: ["laterally",
//                  "medially", 
//                  "laterally",
//                  "anteriorly",
//                  "posteriorly", 
//                  "obliquely"],
//         correctAnswer: "anteriorly"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "The anatomical position refers to the body position as if the person is standing upright with Lower limbs close together with the feet parallel and",
//         answers: ["laterally",
//          "posteriorly", 
//          "anteriorly.",
//          "medially", 
//          "obliquely"],
//          correctAnswer: "laterally"
//     },
//     {   
//         question: "In Anatomical descriptions, there are three imaginary vertical planes.Two are parellel and which one is at right angle to these parellels?",
//         answers: ["median",
//          "sagittal",
//          "frontal/coronal",
//          "transverse",
//          "median sagittal"],
//          correctAnswer: "frontal/coronal"
//     },
//     {
//         question: "Which anatomical plane divides the body into right and left halves?",
//         answers: ["Transverse plane",
//          "Frontal plane",
//          "Sagittal plane",
//          "Median plane",
//          "Coronal plane"],
//         correctAnswer: "Median plane"
//     },
//   ] as Question[]
// }


    
    
    
     

   









    
    
   
//     // {
//     //     "question": "Anatomical descriptions are based on four imaginary planes.Three are vertical. Which one is horizontal?",
//     //     "option1": "median",
//     //     "option1": "sagittal",
//     //     "option1": "frontal",
//     //     "option1": "transverse",
//     //     "option1": "median sagittal",
//     //     "ans": 4
//     // },
    
    
//     {
//         "question": "Which plane divides the body into anterior and posterior parts?",
//         "option1": "Median plane",
//         "option2": "Sagittal plane",
//         "option3": "Frontal plane",
//         "option4": "Transverse plane",
//         "option5": "Oblique plane",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term describes a structure closer to the head?",
//         "option1": "Inferior",
//         "option2": "Caudal",
//         "option3": "Posterior",
//         "option4": "Superior/cranial",
//         "option5": "Lateral",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which movement involves increasing the angle between body parts?",
//         "option1": "Flexion",
//         "option2": "Extension",
//         "option3": "Abduction",
//         "option4": "Adduction",
//         "option5": "Rotation",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term refers to the movement of the thumb to touch another fingertip?",
//         "option1": "Pronation",
//         "option2": "Supination",
//         "option3": "Opposition",
//         "option4": "Eversion",
//         "option5": "Inversion",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the anatomical term for the back surface of the body?",
//         "option1": "Anterior",
//         "option2": "Ventral",
//         "option3": "Posterior",
//         "option4": "Medial",
//         "option5": "Lateral",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term means away from the median plane?",
//         "option1": "Medial",
//         "option2": "Lateral",
//         "option3": "Proximal",
//         "option4": "Distal",
//         "option5": "Superficial",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term is used for the horizontal plane dividing the body into upper and lower parts?",
//         "option1": "Median plane",
//         "option2": "Sagittal plane",
//         "option3": "Frontal plane",
//         "option4": "Transverse plane",
//         "option5": "Oblique plane",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     // {
//     //     "question": "The anatomical position is characterized by all of the following except:",
//     //     "option1": "Body standing upright",
//     //     "option2": "Eyes directed anteriorly",
//     //     "option3": "Arms adjacent to the sides",
//     //     "option4": "Palms facing posteriorly",
//     //     "option5": "Feet parallel",
//     //     "ans": 4
//     // },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term describes the movement of a limb away from the body's midline?",
//         "option1": "Flexion",
//         "option2": "Extension",
//         "option3": "Abduction",
//         "option4": "Adduction",
//         "option5": "Circumduction",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term describes the turning of the sole of the foot inward?",
//         "option1": "Eversion",
//         "option2": "Inversion",
//         "option3": "Pronation",
//         "option4": "Supination",
//         "option5": "Dorsiflexion",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
    
//     {
//         "question": "The term 'ipsilateral' refers to structures located:",
//         "option1": "On the opposite side",
//         "option2": "On the same side",
//         "option3": "On the anterior side",
//         "option4": "On the posterior side",
//         "option5": "On the superior side",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term describes movement that decreases the angle between bones?",
//         "option1": "Extension",
//         "option2": "Flexion",
//         "option3": "Abduction",
//         "option4": "Adduction",
//         "option5": "Rotation",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the correct term for the movement of the foot that brings the toes closer to the shin?",
//         "option1": "Plantarflexion",
//         "option2": "Dorsiflexion",
//         "option3": "Inversion",
//         "option4": "Eversion",
//         "option5": "Circumduction",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term refers to the posterior surface of the hand?",
//         "option1": "Dorsum",
//         "option2": "Palm",
//         "option3": "Sole",
//         "option4": "Plantar",
//         "option5": "Ventral",
//         "ans": 1
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What does the term 'contralateral' refer to?",
//         "option1": "On the same side",
//         "option2": "On the opposite side",
//         "option3": "On the anterior side",
//         "option4": "On the posterior side",
//         "option5": "On the superior side",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term is used to describe the inside or closer to the center of an organ?",
//         "option1": "External",
//         "option2": "Lateral",
//         "option3": "Medial",
//         "option4": "Internal",
//         "option5": "Superficial",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which movement involves a circular motion that combines flexion, extension, abduction, and adduction?",
//         "option1": "Rotation",
//         "option2": "Circumduction",
//         "option3": "Inversion",
//         "option4": "Eversion",
//         "option5": "Supination",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term describes the anatomical position where the body is lying face upward?",
//         "option1": "Prone",
//         "option2": "Supine",
//         "option3": "Lateral",
//         "option4": "Dorsal",
//         "option5": "Ventral",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which anatomical term describes a structure closer to the median plane?",
//         "option1": "Lateral",
//         "option2": "Proximal",
//         "option3": "Distal",
//         "option4": "Medial",
//         "option5": "Superior",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What movement is performed by bringing the shoulder blades together?",
//         "option1": "Elevation",
//         "option2": "Depression",
//         "option3": "Protraction",
//         "option4": "Retraction",
//         "option5": "Rotation",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "The term 'distal' is used to describe a structure that is:",
//         "option1": "Closer to the trunk",
//         "option2": "Farther from the trunk",
//         "option3": "Closer to the head",
//         "option4": "Closer to the feet",
//         "option5": "Nearer to the back",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term is used to describe the anterior surface of the hand?",
//         "option1": "Dorsum",
//         "option2": "Palm",
//         "option3": "Sole",
//         "option4": "Plantar",
//         "option5": "Ventral",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "The term 'proximal' refers to a structure that is:",
//         "option1": "Closer to the trunk",
//         "option2": "Farther from the trunk",
//         "option3": "Closer to the head",
//         "option4": "Closer to the feet",
//         "option5": "Nearer to the back",
//         "ans": 1
//     },
//     // {
//     //     "question": "What term is used to describe the inferior surface of the foot?",
//     //     "option1": "Dorsum",
//     //     "option2": "Palm",
//     //     "option3": "Sole",
//     //     "option4": "Plantar",
//     //     "option5": "Ventral",
//     //     "ans": 3
//     // },
//     // {
//     //     "question":"The branch of Anatomy that provide knowledge of what lies under the skin and what structures are perceptible to touch (palpable) in the living body at rest and in action is known as",
//     //     "option1": "Functional Anatomy",
//     //     "option2": "Developmental Anatomy",
//     //     "option3": "Pathological Anatomy",
//     //     "option4": "Surface Anatomy",
//     //     "option5": "Neuroanatomy",
//     //     "ans": 4
//     // },
//     {
//         "question": "Which movement decreases the angle between the dorsum of the foot and the leg?",
//         "option1": "Plantarflexion",
//         "option2": "Dorsiflexion",
//         "option3": "Inversion",
//         "option4": "Eversion",
//         "option5": "Circumduction",
//         "ans": 2
//     }
    
    
// ]